我曾以为这就是你故事的起点
I used to think this was the beginning of your story.
记忆这东西作风诡异
Memory is a strange thing.
总是让我琢磨不透
It doesn't work like I thought it did.
我们完全受制于时间
We are so bound by time,
要跟随它的节拍
by its order.
好了
Okay.
好了，回到妈妈身边吧
Okay, come back to me.
到妈妈怀里来
Come back to me.
举起手来！
Stick 'em up!
你就是这镇上的警长吗？
Are you the sheriff in this here town?
我拿着挠痒枪，现在要来收拾你了
These are my tickle guns, and I'm gonna get ya.
不要
No.
你想让我去抓你？那你快点逃吧
You want me to chase you? You better run.
我记得故事中间的片段
I remember moments in the middle.
我爱你
I love you.
我恨你！
I hate you!
这就是终点了
And this was the end.
回到妈妈身边
Come back to me.
回到妈妈身边好吗
可现在，我有点不相信起点和终点了
But now I'm not so sure I believe in beginnings and endings.
一些和你人生并无交集的日子，却勾勒出你的故事
There are days that define your story beyond your life.
就好像他们降临的那天
Like the day they arrived.
早上好
Good morning.
- 早上好  - 早上好
- Morning.  - Morning.
怎么就你们几个？
Where is everyone?
好吧，我们上课吧
Okay. Well, let's get started.
今天我们谈下葡萄牙语
Today, we are talking about Portuguese
为什么它的发音和其他罗马语系有较大差别
and why it sounds so different from the other Romance languages.
葡萄牙语发源于加利西亚王国
The story of Portuguese begins in the kingdom of Galicia...
- 抱歉   - 中世纪时期
- Sorry.  - ...in the Middle Ages,
语言被视为一种艺术表达方式
where language was seen as an expression of art.
你有什么新闻想分享吗？
Any news you wanna share?
班克斯博士，你能打开电视机，调到新闻频道吗？
Dr. Banks, can you turn the TV to a news channel?
...来到现场
...arrived here on scene,
警察已经在周边区域设置了路障
but police have already set up a blockade here around the area.
你可以看到，我们已经是尽可能接近了
As you can see, we've gotten just about as close as we can,
可遗憾的是，蒙大拿现在已经完全封锁了
but unfortunately, Montana, right now, is on complete lockdown.
40分钟前，不明物体确认着陆在94号州际公路北面
The object apparently touched down 40 minutes ago just north of I-94.
我们正等候消息，看这是不是艘实验飞船，又或者...
We're waiting to hear if this is perhaps an experimental vessel or...
等下...
Hold on.
我刚得知，还有更多的这类物体
I'm learning that more objects like this have landed
在全球范围内的最少8处地点着陆
at as many as eight other locations around the world.
好，我们可以播？
Yes. Can we?
这是北海道某地
This is from a site in Hokkaido.
这是此时此刻正在全球发生的事件
This is worldwide. It is happening right now.
好吧
Okay.
就到这...  下课了
That's... Class is dismissed.
目前我们只请求大家的配合
For now, we're simply asking for cooperation
等候官方对此物体进行评估
while authorities assess the object.
那你就是说它不是我们国家的？
So, you're saying it's not ours?
你根本不知道它是否来自地球吧？
Do you even know if it's from Earth?
我们正在收集消息，和其他国家协调
We're still collecting information. We're coordinating with other countries.
不只是我们的后院里冒出这么个东西
We are not the only ones to have one of these in our backyard.
如果这是某种寻求和平的第一类接触
If this is some sort of peaceful first contact,
为什么要来12艘
why send 12?
一艘就够了吧
Why not just one?
嗯，我知道，我也看到了
Yeah, I know. I saw that, too.
我不知道，老妈，我跟你看的新闻都一样
I don't know, Mom. I'm watching the same news coverage you are.
老妈啊，别听那个台胡扯
Well, Mom, please don't bother with that channel.
那些人都是白痴，我提醒过你多少次了？
How many times do I have to tell you those people are idiots?
我哪紧张了？
Yeah, well, do I sound nervous?
就是，所以嘛...
Okay, exactly. So...
我？你了解我的，我还不是老样子
Me? Yeah. You know me, I'm about the same.
老妈，我没事
Mom, I'm fine.
好，我会再打给你的，再见
Okay, I'll call you later. Bye.
着陆到现在有差不多8小时了
And at around eight hours after landing,
仍旧没有任何"第一类接触"的迹象
there are still no signs of what might be called "first contact."
不明物体最少有457米高
Now, the objects measure at least 1, 500 feet tall.
据报道，还有2艘不明物体进入俄罗斯领空
Two are reported to have penetrated Russian airspace,
一艘在西伯利亚，另一艘在黑海沿岸
one in Siberia and the other off the coast of the Black...
矗立在海面上
...suspended above the ocean.
目前总计有12艘不明物体降落在全球各地
So far, there are 12 unidentified objects spread across the globe.
它们的降落地点并无明显关联
There is no obvious logic to their locations
没有证据表明这些飞船是...
and no evidence that the ships are even...
如果它的确是某种飞船，也不能排除
...who entertain the idea that if it is a kind of vessel,
它是无人驾驶的可能
it may be unmanned.
不管怎样，我们有应对此类事件的一套方案
Regardless, we have a protocol for scenarios like this, but...
委内瑞拉现场
在经历了不同寻常的周二后
After Tuesday's extraordinary events,
总统今早宣布全国进入紧急状态
the President, this morning, has declared a state of emergency,
仅蒙大拿州，就有约五千名
with as many as 5, 000 National Guard being deployed
国民警卫队进驻
to the state of Montana alone.
边境关闭，航班停飞
Borders are closed and flights have been grounded,
上百万旅客滞留机场
stranding millions of travelers.
人们疯狂抢购汽油，瓶装水和食物
Panic buying of gas, water, and food continues to escalate
联邦政府暂时解除了
and federal authorities have temporarily lifted all caps
对执法部门的加班禁令
on overtime for law enforcement.
烟酒枪械管理署已暂停发放新的持枪许可
The ATF has put a temporary ban on new gun licenses,
迫使许多独立供应商抢购各类武器装备
forcing many independent suppliers of hunting equipment and firearms
并把公众拒之门外
to close their doors to the public.
48小时过去了，在12个UFO着陆点
Forty-eight hours later and no further development...
才2天
Two days.
仍未有新的进展
...from the sight of the 12 UFO...
公众就已经指望我们能解答一切了
And already the public expects us to know the answers.
我是GT韦伯上校
I'm Colonel G.T. Weber.
我们没有正式见过面
We never formally met,
不过2年前，你给情报部门做过波斯语翻译吧？
but two years ago, you did some Farsi translations for Army intelligence.
那些叛军视频的翻译工作你干得很利索
You made quick work of those insurgent videos.
你跟那些叛军打交道也很利索啊
You made quick work of those insurgents.
不管是谁推荐翻译专家，都会把你排在最前面
You are on the top of everyone's list when it comes to translations.
而且你的单一范畴背景调查2年后才失效
And you have another two years in the SSBI.
所以你仍有接触核心机密的许可
So, you still have top-secret clearance.
这也是我选择来你办公室，而不是伯克利的原因
That's why I'm in your office and not at Berkeley.
好吧
Okay.
我有东西想请你翻译
I have something I need you to translate for me.
你们为何而来？
Why are you here?
你们听得懂我们的话吗？
Can you... Can you understand us?
你们来自何方？
Where did you come from?
你现在听过了
Now you heard it.
有什么想法吗？
What do you make of it?
那就是...
Is that...
是的
Yes.
有几个？
How many?
什么几个？
How many what?
说话的有几个？
How many speaking?
2个
Two.
假设他们不是同时开口
Assume they were not speaking at the same time.
你能肯定？他们有嘴吗？
Are you sure? Did they have mouths...
你会如何来翻译这个？
How would you approach translating this?
你能分辨出词语
Do you hear any words?
或者句子吗？
Phrases?
我，我不知道
I don't... I don't know.
那你能告诉我什么？
So, what can you tell me?
我能告诉你的是，仅凭一个音频文件是做不出翻译的
I can tell you that it's impossible to translate from an audio file.
我得亲历现场与他们交谈
I would need to be there to interact with them.
你翻译波斯语时也没在现场啊
You didn't need that with the Farsi translations.
那是因为我已经掌握了波斯语
I didn't need it because I already knew the language.
而这个...
But this, this is...
我知道你打的什么主意
I know what you're doing.
- 揭穿我啊  - 我不会带你去蒙大拿
- Tell me what I'm doing.  - I'm not taking you to Montana.
能接触核心机密的人多了，我不会让那变成
It's all I can do to keep it from turning into a tourist site
你们的旅游景点
for everybody who has a TS clearance.
我只是跟你讲明如何才能做好这份工作
I'm just telling you what it would take to do this job.
我不是来跟你讨价还价的
This is not a negotiation.
我出了这个门，你的机会就没了
If I leave here, your chance is gone.
再见
Good day.
上校
Colonel?
你刚提到了伯克利，你接下来要找丹弗斯吧？
You mentioned Berkeley, are you going to ask Danvers next?
可能吧
Maybe.
在你邀请他前
Before you commit to him,
问他梵文里的“战争”一词，以及翻译过来的意思
ask him the Sanskrit word for "war" and its translation.
在中国和俄罗斯加入联合国的磋商后
An agreement on sharing scientific discoveries looks closer tonight,
有望就共享科学发现达成协议
as Russia and China join talks at the United Nations.
以此同时，全球金融市场陷入危机
Meanwhile, financial markets across the world are in crisis
道琼斯工业指数狂泻2000点
as the Dow Jones Industrial Average fell over 2,000 points
打破了一周跌幅的历史记录
in its worst weekly decline in history.
早上好
Mornin'.
上校
Colonel.
“加维什提” 他说是争论的意思
Gavisti. He says it means "an argument."
你的标准答案是？
What do you say it means?
寻找更多的牛
"A desire for more cows."
收拾好背包
Pack your bags.
好的，给我20分钟
All right, give me 20 minutes?
我们10分钟后起飞
We take off in 10.
班克斯博士，请跟我来
Dr. Banks. Right this way, please.
准备起飞
Contact and ready to approach...
不好意思，班克斯博士，让我检查下你的安全带
Excuse me, Dr. Banks, let me make sure you're properly secured.
你没事吧
You okay?
谢谢
Thanks.
抱歉，刚才听不清你说了什么
Sorry, I couldn't hear what you were saying.
语言是文明的基石
"Language is the foundation of civilization.
是把人们聚到一起的粘合剂
"It is the glue that holds a people together.
也是冲突中最先使用的武器
"It is the first weapon drawn in a conflict."
路易丝，这位是伊恩·唐纳利
Louise, this is Ian Donnelly.
路易丝·班克斯，伊恩·唐纳利
Louise Banks, Ian Donnelly.
这个见面礼不错嘛
It's quite a greeting.
是啊，你的大作
Yeah. Well, you wrote it.
嗯，不过
Yeah, but...
序言都是这么写的
It's the kind of thing you write as a preface,
言简意赅，博取眼球
dazzle them with the basics.
话是漂亮
Yeah. It's great.
可惜说错了
Even if it's wrong.
错了？
It's wrong?
文明的基石并不是语言，而是科学
Well, the cornerstone of civilization isn't language, it's science.
伊恩是阿拉莫斯国家实验室的理论物理学家
Ian is a theoretical physicist from Los Alamos.
你向我汇报工作，不过在“蛋壳”里时，你会和他搭配工作
You'll be reporting to me, but you'll be working with him when you're in the shell.
他们是这样叫不明飞行物的？
That's what they're calling the UFO.
首要任务，搞清他们来自何方，来这里的目的
Priority one. What do they want, where are they from.
除此之外，他们是如何过来的
And beyond that, how did they get here?
他们掌握了超光速旅行吗？
Are they capable of faster-than-light travel?
他们...
Are they...
我专门列了个问题的单子，可以跟你说下
I have a list of questions that, you know, we can go over.
先用二进制序列来欢迎他们
Starting with a series of just a "handshake" of binary sequences...
先别急着问他们各种数学问题
How about we just talk to them
我们从简单交流开始，好吗？
before we start throwing math problems at them?
这正是要你们两个的原因
This is why you're both here.
我负责端咖啡
I'll bring the coffee.
跟外星人一起喝咖啡
Coffee with some aliens.
带他们两个去凯特勒博士那
All right. I want you to take these two to Dr. Kettler.
遵命，长官
Yes, sir.
跟这位上尉去医务室
Follow the captain to Medical.
要花几分钟走下程序，之后我们就开工了
The procedure should take just a few minutes, and then, we'll get started.
背包就交给他们保管吧
These men are gonna take care of your bags.
手机交给我
I'll take your cell phones.
手机
Cell phones.
跟我来
Follow me.
带上这个，任何时候都别取
Put these on. You're gonna wear them at all times.
- 他们来了再说  - 很好
- Not until they're here.  - Great.
长官，他们来了
Sir, they're here.
路易丝·班克斯，伊恩·唐纳利
Louise Banks? Ian Donnelly?
你们上一次用餐是什么时候？
When was the last time either of you have eaten?
- 昨晚  - 我也一样
- Last night.  - Same.
你们上一次做有精神压力的事，是什么时候？
When's the last time you did something stressful?
现在算吗？
Does now count?
说说而已
Just saying.
刚刚被抬进救伤直升机的是谁？
Who was being carted off in the medevac?
不是每个人都能承受这种经历
Not everyone is able to process experiences like this.
我需要给你们抽点血
I'm gonna get some blood from you
然后再给你们打一针疫苗，来抵御各类细菌威胁
and give you an immunization dose that covers a battery of bacterial threats.
你们能签下这个吗？
Would you sign these, please?
请把袖子卷起来
And roll up your sleeves.
你们都没有幽闭恐惧症吧？
Either of you claustrophobic?
- 没有  - 没
- Nope.  - No.
有在服用什么药吗？对什么过敏吗？怀孕呢？
Currently taking any medications? Allergies? Pregnant?
没有
No.
加强剂的药效明显
The booster is a kick to your system,
所以你们可能会有不良反应
so you may experience some side-effects,
诸如恶心，头晕，头疼
nausea, dizziness, headaches,
或者耳鸣之类的
a ringing in your ears like you have tinnitus.
你知道他怎么了吗？
You see what's happening to him?
这个怎么可能？
How does this even work?
读数并无变化，不过...
The readings do not change, but...
我也搞不懂，我们像是爬在纸上的昆虫
I don't know. It's like we're insects on a piece of paper
然后他们让我们自己滚蛋
and they're easing us out of the house.
在112分钟19秒后
At exactly 112 minutes and 19 seconds,
重力开始回升，让我们慢慢滑出房间
the gravity starts to shift and slides us out of the room.
对此你能做出科学上的解释吗？
Have you found a scientific explanation for it?
比如这个变化是为了他们自己？
Like, is it for them?
不，我觉得是照顾我们
No, we think it's for us.
似乎房间内的空气并不流通
The air doesn't seem to circulate inside the chamber,
所以顶多两小时，氧气就耗尽了
so after about two hours, you run out of oxygen.
那输送新鲜空气进房间，18个小时还不够吗？
It doesn't take 18 hours to pump fresh air into a room.
大气
Atmosphere.
你说什么？
Excuse me?
如果他们的大气和地球上的不同
If their atmosphere is different from Earth,
那他们每次打开大门前
it would certainly take hours
就肯定需要数小时来制造适宜氧气浓度和压力来照顾我们
to rebalance the O2 content and pressure for us every time they open their door.
照你这么说，他们随时都可以闷死我们？
So, you're saying they could suffocate us if they wanted?
这位是大卫·哈尔彭，中情局的特工
This is Agent David Halpern with the CIA.
跟我去你们的工作地点吧
Let me get you two to your stations.
好的
Yes, sir.
记住，我们必须尽快搞清这些问题
Remember, we need answers as soon as possible.
他们来做什么，他们来自何方，他们来这的目的
What do they want, where are they from, why they're here.
- 这是首先要解决的  - 好
- This is the priority.  - Yeah.
大家，这位是伊恩·唐纳利博士，他负责带你们队
Everyone, this is Dr. Ian Donnelly. He'll be running this team here.
他们有对什么做出回应吗
Yeah, have they responded to anything?
形状，模式，数字，斐波那契数列？
Shapes, patterns, numbers, Fibonacci?
我们并不懂他们说的话，不过他们对“你好”有回应
We can't tell what they are saying when they respond to "hello,"
别急于求成就行
so don't get ahead of yourself.
你现在有收获吗？
What have you figured out?
我们才刚开始而已
We're just getting started.
- 早上好各位  - 早上好
- Good morning.  - Good morning.
这位是路易丝·班克斯博士
This is Dr. Louise Banks.
她负责带你们队
She'll be heading your team.
- 班克斯博士，很荣幸  - 你好
- Dr. Banks. It's a pleasure meeting you.  - Hi.
班克斯博士会接手沃勒博士的工作
Dr. Banks is taking over the mission from Dr. Walker.
- 很高兴见面  - 班克斯博士，很高兴你能来
- Nice to see you.  - Dr. Banks, glad to see you.
这是15分钟警报
That's your 15-minute warning.
你以前潜过水吗？
You scuba-dive before?
我们要进入何种辐射环境？
What kind of radiation exposure are we walking into?
正常水平，这些只是以防万一
Nominal, these are just for safety.
如果有任何身体接触
So, is there any physical contact with the...
有谁跟我一样讲不出“外星人”吗？
Am I the only one having trouble saying "aliens"?
有堵墙，玻璃状的，你没法接近他们
There's a wall, like a glass wall. You can't get to them.
那他们长啥样的？
So, what do they look like?
你马上就知道了，动作快点吧
You'll see soon enough. Hurry up.
谢谢，请走这边
Thank you. Turn this way, please.
全体人员，等候指令，完毕
All units, stand by. Over.
刚穿防护服可能行动不便，不过你们会适应的
The suits are clumsy at first, but you get used to them.
放到第二辆车上
Load up in the second vehicle.
快点，快点，放到这里
Hurry up, hurry up. Bring it over here.
都搬完了，长官
We're clear over here, sir.
所有设备，长官，这是最后一箱了，这辆车可以走了
All set, sir. This is the last box for this truck. This truck's clear.
出发
Let's go!
我们几分钟后到
We'll be there in a few minutes.
都坐稳抓牢了
Make sure you hold on to something.
我们已进入非军事区
We are now inside the demilitarized zone.
- 距离1.2公里，完毕  - 收到，A小队
- Raise 1.2 klicks. Over.  - Copy, Alpha.
我们会继续监视生命体征，以及行动中的各种信号强度
We'll continue to monitor vitals and signal clarity from operations.
预警机已就位，运转正常
Airpicket's in position and fully operational.
反制措施已就位，等候指令，完毕
Countermeasures in place and ready for deployment. Over.
收到，秃鹫，我们只进行观察，不会贸然采取行动，完毕
Copy, Condor. We will observe, but not initiate. Over.
小心
Watch your step.
我们会保持频道畅通，完毕
We'll keep Alpha channel open. Over.
A小队，请注意，湿度比昨天有所提高
Alpha, be advised. Humidity increased since yesterday.
每隔18小时
Every 18 hours,
飞船底部会打开扇门
the door opens up at the bottom.
我们就从那进去
That's where we go in.
红队已做好准备
Red team on standby.
一切正常，A小队，可以行动，完毕
Zero movement. Alpha detail, clear to proceed. Over.
收到，秃鹫，我们上去了，完毕
Copy, Condor. Beginning our ascent now Over.
3米
Ten feet.
1.5米
Five feet.
0.7米 0.3米
Two. One.
A小队，准许进入通道，完毕
Alpha, clear to enter antechamber. Over.
收到，秃鹫，正在前进，完毕
Copy, Condor. Moving into position. Over.
离目标还有9米
Thirty feet from target.
有不明干扰，不过遥测装置工作正常，完毕
Suit telemetry now full strength, despite unknown interference. Over.
1.5米 0.7米 0.3米
Five feet. Two, one.
氧气浓度20.3%，未检测到污染物，完毕
Oxygen level, 20.3%. No known contaminates. Over.
生命体征正常
Vitals normal.
重力0.97G
Gravity at 0. 97.
无线电信号减弱
Radio signal strength decreasing.
90%, 85%，波动中
90%. 85%. Fluctuating...
嗯，这也行
Yeah, that just happened.
好了，出发吧，时间不等人
All right, let's move. Time is wasting.
你准备好了？你呢？
You ready? You ready?
我们上吧
Let's do it.
秃鹫，我和马克上尉先进去了，完毕
Condor, I'm proceeding first with Captain Marks. Over.
无线电信号强度75%，完毕
Radio signal strength 75%. Over.
已落地，通道里重力微弱，完毕
Landed. Gravity nominal in the antechamber. Over.
一切正常，长官
It's all good, sir.
- 你可以上来了  - 准备接应
- You can proceed.  - Stand by.
好了，上来吧
Okay, bring it up.
生命体征正常
Vitals in line.
无线电信号强度稳定在75%，完毕
Radio signal strength stable at 75%. Over.
你没事吧？
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
班克斯博士
Dr. Banks.
你能行的，去吧
You can do this.
来吧
Come on.
我不知道... 我觉得...
I don't know, I... I think...
接住她
Grab her.
唐纳利博士，你没事吧？
Dr. Donnelly, are you all right?
Dr. Donnelly. You good?
唐纳利博士，你没事吧？请回答，完毕
Dr. Donnelly, are you all right? Please respond. Over.
没事
Yeah.
我的天啊
Holy fuck.
我们去那里面
We're gonna go down there,
你们就可以开工了
and you're gonna start your job.
好的
Okay.
- 好了？全体前进  - 好的
- Okay? Everybody, move out.  - Okay.
A小队已就位
Alpha detail is in position.
小队已就位
Team is in position.
我们进去了
We're on the move.
秃鹫，A队已进入房间
Condor, Alpha's now in the nave.
布置设备和遥测装置，完毕
Setting up equipment and telemetry. Over.
氧气浓度21.3%，完毕
Oxygen level, 21.3%. Over.
下面做什么？
So, what happens now?
等他们现身
They arrive.
班克斯博士？
Dr. Banks.
可以开始了
You can start.
A小队，请直接前往污染物净化室
Alpha detail, proceed directly through the decontamination...
穿过气密门
...to the inner airlock.
在通过气密门前不要停下
Do not stop until you have passed through the airlock doors.
没有正规人员的专业协助
Do not attempt to remove the hazmat suit
不要自行脱下核生化防护服
without proper assistance of authorized personnel.
重复，不要自行脱下核生化防护服
Repeat. Hazmat suits without assistance of authorized personnel.
- 等等，稍等一下  - 好了
- Wait, just a minute. A minute. - All right.
把你的头低下
Keep your head low.
好了
Clear.
- 好了  - 请站出来吧
- All right.  - Step on out, please.
扶着那
Now hold that.
要我走人吗？
Am I fired?
你表现不错，比上一位强
You did better than the last guy.
可我还是高兴不起来
That doesn't make me feel any better.
你们在凌晨两点前要拿出方案来
You both have till 0200 hours to figure something out.
好，那之后呢
Okay, what happens then?
你又回去
You go back in.
UFO降临事件持续发酵
Violence continues to spread across the US today
美国各地今日继续爆发各种骚乱
in the wake of the 12 landings.
总统宣布黄昏至拂晓的强制戒严令
The President has declared a mandatory dusk-to-dawn curfew
而国民警卫队未能遏止住
after the crackdown by the National Guard
全国各地连续三晚的抢掠行为
failed to prevent a third night of looting across the country.
在北达科他州，圣罗伦斯五旬节邪教徒纵火焚烧总部
In North Dakota, 144 members of the St. Lawrence Pentecostal Cult
里面的144名成员恐生还无望
are feared dead after they set their compound ablaze.
他们的网站上宣称，外星人的降临
Their website claims the arrival of the aliens
印证了启示录14:1-5，信徒应当响应
set in motion a prophecy that 12 sets of 12 should "follow the lamb."
这里是711  收到，等候指令
And this is Seven-November. Roger, stand by...
请求已收到
Got that request...
15分钟后我们又要进去了，你有什么新情报吗？
We're up in 15. You got any new intel?
我们在回放一些他们的声音
Yeah, we've been playing back some of their sounds.
有什么进展吗？
Where does that get you?
他们播放音频回应我们时，声源不明
Well, they play audio back at us from an unseen source.
什么音频？
Audio of what?
就房间里的一些谈话，还有对话里的随机片段
It's bits of conversation from the room, random clips of dialogue.
我们一无所获
Really, we... We have nothing.
距“蛋壳”开启还有14分钟
T-minus 14 minutes to shell access.
你收到我的信号了吗？
Are you receiving my signal?
收到了，正在发送
Yes. It's sending.
- 好，谢谢  - 好的，希望你有收获
- Okay, thanks.  - Okay. Good hunting.
出发了
Heading out.
检查无线电，听得到我说话吗？
Checking in for radio. Are you receiving me?
你的声音宏亮清晰
You're coming in loud and clear.
祝你好运，博士
Good luck, Doctor.
氧气瓶状态：1到6皆满
距“蛋壳”开启还有9分钟
T-minus nine minutes to shell access.
那个做什么用的？
What's that for?
涂写用的视觉教具
A visual aid.
听着，他们不开口的话，我一辈子都甭想学会他们的语言
Look, I'm never going to be able to speak their words if they are talking.
可要是他们有文字之类的，或简单的视觉交流方式
But they might have some sort of written language or basis for visual communication.
好吧，让我们试试
Okay. Let's get started.
人类
Human.
"Human."
我是人类
I'm human.
你是什么？
What are you?
人类
Human.
收到，A队
Affirmative, Alpha...
- 天啊
Oh, my God.
你录下来了吗？
Are you getting this?
是的，长官，正传回大本营
Yes, sir. It's uploading back to base camp.
路易丝
Louise.
这真是难以置信啊
That's incredible.
人类
Human.
很好
Okay.
很好... 慢点啊，伙计
Okay, slow down, fellas.
慢点
Slow down.
我不是想否认你取得的成果
I don't wanna take away from your success in there,
班克斯博士，就只有这一招了吗？
but, Dr. Banks, is this really the right approach?
交他们读书认字？
Trying to teach 'em how to speak and read?
这得花多久啊
That's gotta take longer.
你不懂，这会事半功倍的
You're wrong. It's faster.
你在这里做的每件事，我都要给一屋子的人解释
Everything you do in there I have to explain to a room full of men
而他们只关心一个问题：“这会给我们带来怎样的麻烦”
whose first and last question is, "How can this be used against us?"
所以你得给我令人信服的理由
So, you're gonna have to give me more than that.
袋鼠
Kangaroo.
什么意思？
What is that?
1770年
In 1770,
船长詹姆斯·库克的船只在澳大利亚沿岸搁浅
Captain James Cook's ship ran aground off the coast of Australia,
他带队登陆，并见到了当地的土著
and he led a party into the country and they met the Aboriginal people.
其中一位水手指着把幼崽装在兜里
One of the sailors pointed at the animals that hop around
在地上蹦来蹦去的动物
and put their babies in their pouch,
问它们叫什么，土著回答“Kanguru”
and he asked what they were, and the Aborigines said, "Kanguru."
你想表明什么？
And the point is?
很久以后他们才搞懂“Kanguru”的意思是“我听不懂”
It wasn't until later that they learned that "kanguru" means "I don't understand."
所以，我在房间里用这个是为了化解误会
So, I need this so that we don't misinterpret things in there,
不然得耗费10倍的时间
otherwise this is gonna take 10 times as long.
这理由勉强能交差
I could sell that for now.
下次对话前，你必须把要用的词
But I need you to submit your vocabulary words
拟个单子给我
before the next session.
好
Fair.
请别忘了土著人的遭遇
And remember what happened to the Aborigines.
一个更先进的种族差点令他们灭亡
A more advanced race nearly wiped 'em out.
你讲的故事不错
It's a good story.
谢谢
Thanks.
是杜撰的
It's not true.
但管用就行
But it proves my point.
人类？
我觉得我们能还原出
We think we were able to reproduce
一些素数序列给他们
some prime number sequences back at them.
也算是有收获
So, that's something.
祝贺你，学到鹦鹉的本事了
Well, congratulations. You're a parrot.
意义远不止如此，你个自大狂
Well, it's a lot more than that, you cheeky bastard.
装糊涂吗？他们似乎搞不懂我们的几何学
Don't you see? They can't seem to follow our algebra.
反而对高深点的，更有共鸣
But complex behaviors? That clicks.
这根本没道理啊，不是吗？
Well, that doesn't make any sense at all, does it?
问题是，不是每个人都认同我们和外星人开诚布公的做法
The problem is, not everyone shares our policy of being open with the aliens.
这位是尚将军
Have you met General Shang?
他主宰着局势走向
Call sign for him is "Big Domino."
不管尚做什么，最少也会有4个国家效仿
Whatever Shang does, at least four other nations will follow.
- 路易丝，我们今天休整一下  - 好
- Louise, you have to gain ground today.  - Okay.
- 你给我准备好词语单了吗？  - 准备好了
- You have a vocabulary list for me?  - I do.
你要教他们认识你和伊恩的名字？
You're gonna teach them your name and Ian's?
是的，他们有名字的话，也会教给我们
Yes, so that we can learn their names, if they have names,
然后再介绍代词
and then introduce pronouns later.
这些都是小学教的
These are all grade-school words.
吃，走
"Eat." "Walk."
给我解释下
Help me understand.
好
Okay.
别，别擦，别擦上面的
No, no, no, not the top!
“你们到访地球的目的？”
好，这就是你想问的，对吧？
Okay, this is where you wanna get to, right?
- 就是这个  - 好
- That is the question.  - Okay.
那我们首先要确定，他们懂得什么是“问题”
So, first we need to make sure that they understand what a question is.
本质是我们发起请求
Okay? The nature of a request for information
来获取信息
along with a response.
然后我们还得解释清楚
Then, we need to clarify
“你”跟“你们”有什么区别
the difference between a specific "you" and a collective "you,"
因为我们并不关心某个外星人被派来做什么
because we don't want to know why Joe Alien is here.
而是想搞清他们共同到访的目的
We want to know why they all landed.
而目的又需要懂得意图
And "purpose" requires an understanding of intent.
我们得搞清这是他们自觉的选择
We need to find out, do they make conscious choices
亦或是受本能驱使
or is their motivation so instinctive
以至于对提问根本不会有反应
that they don't understand a "why" question at all.
而重中之重，我们得跟他们建立起足够的词汇量
And... And biggest of all, we need to have enough vocabulary with them
能让我们明白他们的回答
that we understand their answer.
懂了
I get it.
遵照你的单子
Stick to your list.
千万...别乱加词进去
Just don't add anything to it.
重力0.97G，氧气浓度21.4%，完毕
Gravity, 0.97. Oxygen level, 21.4%. Over.
秃鹫，A队已就位
Condor, Alpha's now in the main.
正布置设备和遥测装置，完毕
Setting up equipment and telemetry. Over.
我们开始吧
Let's get started.
路易丝
"Louise."
路易丝，我叫路易丝
Louise. I am Louise.
那是什么？
What is that?
那是新符号吗？我分不清
Is that a new symbol? I can't tell.
不是吧，我觉得还是表示“人类”的符号
I don't know I think it's the symbol for "human" again.
只是收尾处略弯了点，或许这表示提问
It just has a little curl on the end, maybe to indicate a question.
我也不敢肯定
I don't know.
我也一样，路易丝
I don't know, Louise.
我觉得他们没明白
I think they're getting confused.
班克斯博士，我们继续下一个词吧
Dr. Banks, perhaps we should move on to the next word.
班克斯博士
Dr. Banks?
- 没事的  - 什么情况？
- It's okay, Nate.  - What's going on?
嘿，嘿，你在做什么？
Hey, hey, hey. What are you doing?
- 我没事  - 你疯了吗？
- Yeah, I'm fine.  - Are you insane?
得让他们见到我的真面目
They need to see me.
她要脱掉核生化防护服  班克斯博士！
She's taking off her hazmat suit. Dr. Banks!
你没事吧？
Is it okay?
你有感染的危险
You're risking contamination.
得让他们见到我的真面目
They need to see me.
班克斯博士
Dr. Banks.
她朝玻璃墙走去了
She's walking towards the screen.
要终止任务吗？
Should we abort?
请求收到，等候口头指令
Request noted. Stand by for frag order.
回到你们的位置
Go back to your stations.
这才算是正式见面
Now that's a proper introduction.
好了
Okay.
路易丝
"Louise."
我叫路易丝
I am Louise.
伊恩，你不介绍自己吗？
Ian, you want to introduce yourself?
好吧
Yeah.
路易丝
Louise.
豁出去了
Screw it.
人都有一死，对吧？
Everybody dies, right?
长官，唐纳利也脱掉了防护服
Sir, Donnelly is taking off his hazmat suit.
准许终止任务？
Permission to abort?
继续对话进程
Continue the session.
伊恩
Ian.
路易丝
Louise.
你呢？
You.
你们叫什么？
Who are you?
这应该是他们的名字
I think those are their names.
他们也有名字
They have names.
我们该如何称呼他们呢？
So, what are we gonna call them?
我不知道
I don't know.
我推荐阿波特和科斯特洛
I was thinking Abbott and Costello.
阿波特和科斯特洛是1940到1950年间好莱坞著名的喜剧搭档
好
Yeah.
- 好吗？  - 好，很好
- Yeah?  - Yeah, I like it.
很好
I like it.
一队人员，下车后
Team 1, exit your vehicle
直接前往污染物净化室
and proceed directly ahead to the decontamination tent.
在进入设备间前，请别取下你们的面具
Leave your respirator on until you reach the equipment room.
我知道
I know.
二队人员，下车后直接前往污染物净化室
Team 2, exit your vehicles and continue to the decontamination tent.
在进入设备间前
Leave your respirators on
千万别取下你们的面具
and do not hesitate until you reach the equipment room.
你感觉如何？
How do you feel?
疲劳过度
Overworked.
不用我多说你也明白，这样做有多危险
Well, I guess I don't need to tell you, you're putting yourself at risk.
并没有辐射中毒的迹象
There are no signs of radiation poisoning yet.
等你的血检出来后，我们再确认
We'll see how your blood tests look.
目前嘛，我再给你打一针加强剂
For now, I'm gonna give you another boost.
好
Okay.
没有辐射中毒
No radiation.
我们没查出任何异样
Nothing else we can detect either,
不过为了以防外一，我还是给他们打了加强剂
but I'd give 'em a strong cocktail regardless.
这是我们头一回取得实质进展
It's the first time we've made significant progress.
好吧
All right.
我们就冒这一回险
We'll take the risk.
- 宝贝  - 那边到底什么情况？
- Okay, honey...  - What is going on there?
- 宝贝  - 你一个字都不能透露？
- Honey.  - Is there anything you can tell me?
不能，你不用担心，好吗？
No... You don't need to worry, okay?
- 我怎么能不担心？  -冷静点
- How can I not worry?  - Just calm down.
冷静点
Just calm down.
贝基吵着问我，那些怪物会不会把爹地杀了
Becky asked me if the monsters are going to kill Daddy,
宝贝，那是不可能的
Honey, it's not gonna happen.
一定要注意安全
Just stay safe.
你不用担心
You don't need to worry.
请务必，我好害怕
Please, I'm so scared.
所有初级外星语言学家和科研人员必须遵守
All junior xenolinguistics and science personnel must observe
宵禁命令，除非有指挥官的特别授权
general curfew unless expressly authorized
可以进行加班工作
for extended work hours by unit COs.
宵禁每晚10点开始
Curfew in effect as of 2200 hours.
通知到所有晚班人员，消防人员，守夜人员
Notice to all late workers, fire watchers and night staff.
即刻生效，宵夜整晚供应
Effective immediately, midnight rations will be served all night.
我们仍然对七肢桶的许多方面一无所知
Here are some of the many things we don't know about heptapods.
hepta源自古希腊语，表示七，pod，表示脚
Greek. Hepta, "Seven. " Pod, "Foot."
七只脚，故称七肢桶
"Seven feet." Heptapod.
他们是何方神圣？
Who are they?
试图从任何有意义的角度来回答
Trying to answer thisin any meaningful way
都困难重重
is hampered by the fact that,
因为外界既看不到、也听不到他们
outside being able to see them and hear them,
七肢桶不留下任何蛛丝马迹
the heptapods leave absolutely no footprint.
他们宇宙飞船的化学组成仍未可知
The chemical composition of their spaceship is unknown.
“蛋壳”不产生废物，不排出气体，也没有辐射
The shell emits no waste, no gas, no radiation.
假设“蛋壳”之间有互有通讯
Assuming that the shells communicate with each other,
那他们手段高明，悄无声息
they do so without detection.
“蛋壳”内的空气不会被超声波或光波干扰
The air between the shells is untroubled by sonic emission or light wave.
他们是科学家，还是观光客？
Are they scientists or tourists?
他们是科学家的话，为什么提问并不积极
If they're scientists, they don't seem to ask a lot of questions.
他们为什么要停在现在的地方？
Why did they park where they did?
世界上最富盛名的专家也是一头雾水
The world's most decorated experts can't crack that one.
最受推崇的理论是，他们选择的地点都是
The most plausible theory is that they chose places on Earth
地球上闪电出现机率最低的
with the lowest incidence of lightning strikes.
可也有个别例外
But there are exceptions.
另一种候选理论是，这些地点都跟上世纪80年代
The next most plausible theory is that Sheena Easton had a hit song
席娜·伊斯顿：苏格兰著名歌星
席娜·伊斯顿的流行歌曲有关  所以... 我们只是瞎猜
at each of these sites in 1980. So, we just don't know.
他们之间如何交流？
How do they communicate?
路易丝的工作成果，令我们自惭形秽
Here, Louise is putting us all to shame.
我们取得的首个突破是发现七肢桶
The first breakthrough was to discover that there's no correlation
的书写和口语之间并无关联
between what a heptapod says and what a heptapod writes.
伊恩走路
不像任何人类文字，他们的书写是会意象形语标文字
Unlike all written human languages, their writing is semasiographic.
只传达意思，并无对应的发音
It conveys meaning. It doesn't represent sound.
或许我们的书写，在他们看来是多余的
Perhaps they view our form of writing as a wasted opportunity,
浪费了第二个交流渠道
passing up a second communications channel.
我们要感谢巴基斯坦的朋友
We have our friends in Pakistan
他们贡献了对七肢桶书写的研究
to thank for their study of how heptapods write.
因为和说话不同，语标不受时间限制
Because, unlike speech, a logogram is free of time.
与他们的飞船、身体相似
Like their ship or their bodies,
他们的书写文字不存在先后顺序
their written language has no forward or backward direction.
语言学家称之为非线性拼写
Linguists call this "nonlinear orthography,"
这不禁让人疑问：“他们也是这样思考的吗？”
which raises the question, "Is this how they think?"
想象你要用双手写一个句子
Imagine you wanted to write a sentence using two hands,
同时从2头开始
starting from either side.
你得想好要写的每一个字
You would have to know each word you wanted to use
以及它们占用的空间
as well as how much space that it would occupy.
而七肢桶在2秒内就能轻松写出
A heptapod can write a complex sentence
一个复杂的句子
in two seconds, effortlessly.
而我们做个最简单的回复，都要花上一个月
It's taken us a month to make the simplest reply.
下一步，扩充词汇量
Next, expanding vocabulary.
路易丝认为怎么都要花上一个月
Louise thinks it could easily take another month to be ready for that.
嘿
Hey.
韦伯正找你呢
Weber's looking for you.
嗯，你以为我躲在这干嘛？
Yeah, well, why do you think I'm hiding out here?
上来啊
Come on up.
来
Come on.
谢谢
Thanks.
这地方不错吧？
Nice out here, huh?
嗯，风景不错
Yeah, it's a nice view.
远离喧嚣
Away from the noise.
其实，我刚好想到你
You know, I was just thinking about you.
你处理语言的方式挺像数学家
You approach language like a mathematician.
你自己也知道吧？
You know that, right?
我就当你是恭维我啊
I will take that as a compliment.
就是恭维
Yeah, well, it is.
多亏了你
It's...
我们才能避开那些沟通陷阱
I watch you steer us around these communication traps
不然我还蒙在鼓里
that I didn't even know existed.
说的什么啊
Say what?
我单身就是这个原因吧
I guess that's why I'm single.
不是打击你，懂得去沟通还不足以
Trust me, you can understand communication
让你脱单啊
and still end up single.
我总觉得那里面发生的一切
I feel like everything that happens in there
都和我们俩有关
comes down to the two of us.
这是好事，对吧？你和我？
Yeah, it's a good thing though, right? You and I?
整天和些废物一起工作，你也受不了吧？
Have you seen the jokers that we're working with?
能遇到你，真是老天有眼
I'm glad I got you.
外星人危机 第25天 委内瑞拉
外星人危机 第25天 塞拉利昂
伦敦  拯救我们的种族！
今晚，第一张外星人的照片开始疯传
Tonight, the first photograph of the aliens goes viral.
环保组织警告，蒙大拿存在的主要风险因子
Biological contamination is a major risk factor at the Montana site,
就是生化污染
so say environmental pressure groups.
在华盛顿，80万市民走上街头
Eight-hundred thousand march on Washington
抗议政府的危机应对
to protest the government's handling of the crisis.
别走开，还有更多的特别报道
All this, and more special coverage.
...有人在那东西里和外星人接触
First contact with whoever it is that is inside that thing,
猜猜是谁在导演？当然是政府啊
and who do we have running the show? The government.
没错，就是这个政府
That's right, folks. The same government
搞砸了我们的医疗保险，搞垮了我们的军队
who ruined our healthcare and bankrupted our military.
瞧瞧这些人
Look at these people.
他们大多数人连枪都没有
Most of them don't even have guns.
面对着可能的全面入侵
We could be facing a full-scale invasion,
我们的总统却一味忍让
and our president is just willing to sit back
对他们采取绥靖政策
and let them waltz in and take our country.
我们就要完蛋了，醒醒吧大家！
We are falling asleep at the wheel, people.
你们知道我说的是事实，肯定知道
You know what I'm talking about. I know you do.
现在我们应该展现武力,威慑对方
What if the smartest thing we could do right now
这才是上上策吧？
would be to give them a show of force?
最好是向他们发出警告
I'm talking about a shot across the bow
我想了解听众朋友的观点
I wanna hear what you think.
请拨打热线电话，发表下你对目前局势的看法
Caller number one, you're on the air. What do you think about all this?
这个词怎么念？
What's this word?
行星
"Planet."
不，不
No, no.
比方说，地球是颗行星
That's, like... The Earth is a planet.
我在加略特老师课上做的东西，你要看吗？
Want to see my project from Miss Garriott's class?
好啊，小肉鼻
Yeah, little nose.
我们要做自己的电视节目
We had to make up our own TV show.
如果我们有的话
If we had one.
- 这两个人是谁？  - 你和爸爸
- And who are those two people?  - That's you and Dad.
节目叫“爸爸妈妈与动物交谈”
The show is called Mommy and Daddy Talk to Animals.
真有爱
Well, it's lovely.
好吧
Okay.
你有权不开心，因为你爸爸和我...
You know it's okay to be sad that your dad and I...
我懂，我没事
I know. I'm not.
我们俩都很爱你
'Cause we both love you very much.
我懂，这只是幅卡通，不代表什么
I know. It's just a cartoon. Not real.
路易丝？
Louise?
你还好吗？
You all right?
嗯
Yeah.
嗯，没什么
Yeah, I'm fine.
就是我想给你解释，也可能会力不从心
I'm not sure it's something I can explain.
你没去凯文医生那检查下吗？
When was your last checkup with Dr. Kettler?
我没事
I'm okay.
我出去透透气
I'm gonna get some air.
不用担心
I'm okay.
- 好吧  - 我没事
- All right.  - I'm fine. Yeah.
你感觉好些了吗？
How you feeling?
我需要补充睡眠，不过还挺得住
I need some sleep, but I'm fine.
真的？
Yeah.
我最近在研读一种理论，里面讲到
You know, I was doing some reading about this idea that
如果你全身心的钻研一门外语
if you immerse yourself into a foreign language,
整个人都会骤然改变
that you can actually rewire your brain.
嗯，是萨丕尔-沃夫假说
Yeah, the Sapir-Whorf Hypothesis.
这种理论
The theory that...
这种理论认为
It's the theory that
你所讲的语言能决定你的思维模式
the language you speak determines how you think and...
对，这能影响到你的世界观
Yeah. It affects how you see everything. It was...
我想问下
I'm curious,
你做梦都在说他们的语言吗？
are you dreaming in their language?
我是做过这样的梦，可我觉得...
I may have had a few dreams, but I don't...
并不会因此而误了工作
I don't think that that makes me unfit to do this job.
你有睡觉吗？
Did you sleep?
睡了会儿
A little.
你懂中文吗?
Do you know Mandarin?
变化了
It is shifting.
你马上要听的声音是来自中国军队的最高统帅
The voice you're about to hear belongs to China's military chief,
尚将军
General Shang.
戴上耳机
Pull it up.
这有卫星信号，你可以边看边听
We got a satellite feed here of who he's talking to,
确定他说了什么
if you want to look.
等等，往回倒
Wait, go back.
停
Stop.
他说这12艘船都会给我们先进技术
He's saying that each of the 12 is offering advanced technology.
再回倒，播放
And back again. And play.
“我们的科学家团队正尝试破译集合”
"Our science team is attempting to decode the sets."
“集合”，我不明白是什么意思
"Sets." I don't know what that means.
能获取优势之类的
Something about advantage.
“西服，荣誉，花朵”
"Suits, honor, and flowers."
我不...
I don't...
我不明白，就这样
I don't know, that's all.
我也搞不明白
I don't know what it means either.
一小时前，中国的军队开始集结
An hour ago, China mobilized forces.
现在俄罗斯也响应了
And now, Russia is following suit.
尚打定主意要行动了
Shang's about to start something.
跟着西装（跟牌）... 西装...
Following suit, "suits".
是序数牌，字牌，花牌
Suits. Honor. Flowers.
上校，这些都是麻将里的牌
Colonel, those are all tile sets in mahjong.
天啊，难道他们
God, are they...
他们在用游戏和七肢桶沟通吗？
Are they using a game to converse with their heptapods?
有可能...这又如何？
Maybe. Why?
假如我不教英语，而是教七肢桶国际象棋
Well, let's say that I taught them chess instead of English.
通过游戏来进行每句对话
Every conversation would be a game,
在对弈的过程中传递每个想法，只有胜负之分
every idea expressed through opposition, victory, defeat.
你还不明白？
You see the problem?
如果我只给你把锤子
If all I ever gave you was a hammer...
你看什么都像钉子
Everything's a nail.
我们必须问重大问题
We need to ask the big question.
等不了了
Ready or not.
对，所以...
Right, so...
好，告诉我你所使用的温度，好吗？
Okay, let me know what temperature you use, okay?
不对，这个和以前一样
No, this is the same as before.
- 看  - 我...
- See.  - I...
嗯，不，可是在3和4之间
Yeah, no, but between three and four.
- 好了，该走了  - 好的
- All right, time to go.  - Okay.
还有96分钟可以进行对话，完毕
Ninety-six minutes remaining in the session. Over.
好
Okay.
“七肢桶 目的”
Heptapod's purpose.
“七肢桶 目的 地球” 你们来地球的目的？
Heptapod purpose. Earth. What is your purpose?
只有科斯特洛一人？
Do we only have Costello?
很好，你出现了
Okay. There you are.
他说了什么？
What does it say?
给武器
"Offer weapon."
你可是亲眼看到他们写的
But you saw what they wrote.
用的那个词他们还没完全搞明白
Using a word they don't fully understand.
- 这可能只是个请求  - 或者是警告
- It could be just a request.  - Or a warning.
够了
Enough!
路易丝
Louise?
我们并不知道他们
We don't know if they understand
是否分得清武器和工具
the difference between a weapon and a tool.
我们的语言如同文化般繁杂
Our language, like our culture, is messy,
有时一个词能表达两种意思
and sometimes one can be both.
他们很可能想说的是，让我们给他们东西
I think it's quite possible that they're asking us to offer them something,
而不是反过来，就像贸易的雏形
not the other way around, like the first part of a trade.
那除了这两个词，我们如何才能搞清他们的意图?
So, how do we clarify their intentions beyond those two words?
我再回去
Well, I go back in.
我们立刻返回，找出真相
Right away, we go back in and we clear this up.
实际操作要比那麻烦得多
It's more complicated than that.
哪麻烦了，你说说看？
How is it more complicated than that?
上校，国防部长要跟你通话
Colonel, the Secretary of Defense is on the line for you.
在我们搞清这个之前，一定要保守秘密
We need to sit on this information till we know what it means.
不能让我们的敌人知道了
So, we aren't sharing it with our enemies.
我们还必须考虑一种可能性
We have to consider the idea
我们的访客想以此来挑拨我们内斗
that our visitors are prodding us to fight among ourselves
直到仅有一方胜出
until only one faction prevails.
你这么说根本没有依据
There's no evidence of that.
明显有
Sure there is.
随便翻开本史书
Just grab a history book.
英国同印度，德国同卢旺达
The British with India, the Germans with Rwanda.
在匈牙利他们还专门造了个词
They even got a name for it in Hungary.
嗯
Yeah.
我们的世界是多极的
We're a world with no single leader.
七肢桶不可能只挑选一国来打交道
It's impossible to deal with just one of us.
现在又提到了武器
And with the word "weapon" now...
我是哈尔彭
Halpern.
是的
Yes, sir.
收到，等候指令
Copy that. Waiting for instructions.
还没确认
No confirmation yet.
继续等待
Standing by.
有消息吗？
Anything?
他们说了什么
What did they say?
中国和俄罗斯都离线了，还指望他们能说什么
China and Russia are off the grid. They aren't speaking to anyone.
不管他们在上一次对话中了解到什么，都被吓到了
Whatever they learned in their last session has them spooked.
遵命，长官
Yes, sir.
命令我们也离线
We have orders to do the same.
等等，这些可是我们的盟友
Wait, these are our allies.
上校，你不能这么做
Colonel, you can't shut us down.
- 关掉我们的无线电  - 照办
- Put us on radio silence.  - Do it.
七肢桶给我们的消息是...
We received a message from the...
该死！
Damn it!
我们需要保持对话
We need to be talking to each other.
你想跟他们对话？先搞清这是什么意思
You wanna talk to them? Find out what this means.
大本营之间的通讯已中断
Base-camp talk is now offline.
- 所有的翻译...  - 还没确认，他们都离线了
- All interpreters... - No confirmation. They're offline.
...都退下，向部门联络员报道
...stand down and report to unit coordinators.
我们之前都没有重启过对话
We've never re-entered a session before.
路易丝，相信我好吗？我们还来得及
Look, Louise, trust me, okay? We've got time.
只需要加快进度，对吧？
We've just gotta step on it, all right?
“使用武器”
"Use weapon."
这是外星人发出的信息
This is the alien message
促使中国政府在今天
said to have provoked the Chinese government
下令让他们的科学家退出国际合作任务
to withdraw their scientists from the international mission today.
在一份声明中，尚将军说道
In a statement, General Shang said,
对外星人的分化图谋，中方表示遗憾
"China no longer trusts the aliens who want to divide us.
会以保护全人类为己任
"Humanity must be protected."
中国请求联合国召开紧急会议
China has asked for immediate talks at the UN.
A19，这是秃鹫，完毕
Alpha one-niner, this is Condor. Over.
A19，这是秃鹫
Alpha one-niner, this is Condor.
请讲，完毕
Come in. Over.
马克斯上尉，这是秃鹫
Captain Marks, Condor.
没有收到回复，收到的话，请回答
Not receiving transmission. Squelch twice if you hear mine.
马克斯上尉，护送人员被要求停止一切行动
Captain Marks, all escort groups are ordered to cease all activity.
不，不行，班克斯博士，你不能进去
No, no, no. Dr. Banks, you can't go in there.
就让我问一个问题
We just need to ask one question.
班克斯博士，这次对话已经结束了，你不能...
Dr. Banks, the session is finished. You can't...
你不能再进去，会有危险的
You can't go back in. It's dangerous.
我们只需要5分钟，别紧张
Look, we just need five minutes. Don't sweat it.
马克斯，放他们进去
Marks, let them go.
嘿，阿波特
Hey, Abbott.
那么，我们该如何称呼？第37次对话？
So, what are we calling this, session 37?
不，第36次对话第二段
No, 36, part two.
好吧
Okay.
嗯
Yeah.
怎么他们单独进去了？
Why they on their own?
我一直在试着联系马克斯上尉
We've been attempting to hail Captain Marks.
护送小队不肯回应，长官
The escort units are not responding, sir.
为什么不回应？
Why not?
派出安保人员
Send security.
给武器，问号
"Offer weapon. Question mark."
你们要给我们什么吗？
Are you offering us something?
“技术，设备，方法”？
"Technology. Apparatus. Method"?
嗯，瞧见了吗？这是不同的词
Yeah, see, this is a different word.
这个弧线，它要臃肿得多
This segment, it's a lot busier.
给
"Give.
技术
"Technology.
现在
"Now."
他在做什么？
What's he doing?
上尉，看你十点钟方向
Captain, on your 10.
反叛人员必须立即逮捕
Mutineers are to be apprehended without engaging.
不能让他们激怒我们的访客，完毕
We don't want to risk antagonizing our visitors. Over.
安保分队接近中，长官  4分钟后到达
Security detail inbound, sir. T-minus four minutes remaining.
我们得拿出对策
We need to see this through.
好了，武器上膛，做好准备
Okay, this is it. Lock and load.
只要拖住他们，就能确保任务完成
We just need to hold them off until it's done.
明白 只需警告性射击，压制住他们
Copy that. Warning shots and suppressive fire only.
都上膛，找掩护
Load up and get to cover.
保持镇定，尽量不要造成伤亡
Stay fresh and we can avoid casualties.
阿波特想让我去屏障那写
Abbott wants me to write on the barrier.
你有这个本事？
Can you even do that?
我不知道
I don't know.
我用双手写不了
I can't do it with both hands.
路易丝
Louise.
那是什么声音？
What is that?
- 自由开火  - 快过来，我中枪了，我中枪了
- Free fire!  - Over there! I'm hit! I'm hit!
嘿，嘿，别忙着起来
Hey, hey, hey. Take it easy.
你遭受了脑震荡
You suffered a concussion.
还是躺着吧
Just lay back.
你感觉如何？
How are you feeling?
伊恩怎么样了？
How is Ian?
和你一样 没什么大碍
Same as you. He's okay.
谁...
Who...
是谁干的？
Who did this?
几个小兵 看电视看傻了
Some soldiers. Been watching too much TV.
那是什么？
What is that?
别紧张，别紧张
Now, take it easy. Take it easy.
营地不再安全了
The site's no longer secure.
我们正等待疏散
We're standing by to evacuate.
伊恩呢？
Where's Ian?
大约10分钟前，韦伯把他叫走了
Weber came and got him maybe 10 minutes ago.
得知你没事，他才肯离开的
But he wouldn't leave until he knew you were okay.
帐篷里的人都在连轴转
The whole tent is on the clock
想破解七肢桶给你的那个天书
to figure out whatever it is you were given up there.
全都在这了？
This is all of it.
图像信号没有因爆炸而中断？
The feed wasn't interrupted by the explosion?
据我所知是这样
Not as far as we can see.
有你能看懂的吗？
You see something?
我还不知道
I don't know yet.
先得把我和路易丝的团队都召集起来
I'm gonna need my team to get together with Louise's team.
这需要大家群策群力
I need everybody working on this.
我们还不能离开
We cannot leave.
很高兴你醒了
Glad to see you're awake.
我们必须回去，我们得向他们解释，这不是我们的过错
We need to go back in and we need to explain to them this wasn't our fault.
- 我们不能再回去了  - 我们必须回去，跟他们解释
- We can't go back inside.  - We have to tell them... We have to.
在那里面发生的是一起袭击
What happened in there was an attack.
我们可以指望最好的结果，可也要做好迎接报复的准备
We can hope for the best, but I have orders to prepare for retaliation.
我们或许只能疏散
We may have to evacuate.
那样做就错了，只要他们还停在那，我们就应该坚守
No, that's the wrong move. As long as they stay, we have to stay.
他们并没飞走
Well, they're not leaving.
我怎么觉得要出大事？
Why does this feel worse?
中国摆出了进攻架势
China is on the offensive.
他们正调动军队，准备对外星人飞船发起攻击
They're positioning their military to blow the alien vessel right out of the sky.
一旦开战
And if this happens,
我们不能坐以待毙，所以开始准备吧
we can't sit around waiting for retaliation, so get prepared.
空军和陆军正待命中
The Air Force and infantry are standing by.
遵命
Yes, sir.
突发新闻
今晚，中国成为首个向外星人
Tonight, China becomes the first world power
宣战的世界大国
to declare war against the aliens.
在联合国的外交斡旋宣告失败后
Following the failure of diplomatic efforts at the United Nations,
中国对外证实，他们的语言专家在今晚
China has confirmed that its language experts have, tonight,
向上海的外星人下达了最后通牒
delivered an ultimatum at the Shanghai site.
在一份电视声明中
In a televised statement, General Shang,
中国人民解放军最高统帅，尚将军
Chairman of the People's Liberation Army,
限令外星人24小时内撤出中国
said the aliens have 24 hours to leave Chinese territory
不然将遭到毁灭性打击
or face destruction.
他还敦促其他国家的领导人与中国联合起来
And he urged all other world leaders to unite with China
采取一致行动
and take a similar stance.
巴基斯坦，俄罗斯和苏丹都在本国的着陆点
With a huge buildup of forces at their landing sites,
集结起大军 预计会紧随中国采取行动
Pakistan, Russia, and Sudan are thought to be following China's lead.
这肯定有章可循
It can't be random.
我们怎么也得研究数年
It's going to take us years.
这里该用什么术语？
What's this term here?
妈妈
Mom.
老妈？
宝贝怎么了？
Sweetie?
用来形容那个的术语
What's this term for that thing like a...
像是科技术语
Like a technical term?
就是我们达成协议，双方都有收获那种？
Where we make a deal and we both get something out of it?
妥协吗？
"Compromise."
不是
No.
就好比竞争一样，但结果令双方都满意
Like, it's a competition, but both sides end up happy.
是双赢吗？
Like a win-win.
还要更有科学性
More science-y than that.
你要问科学方面的，去打给你父亲
If you want science, call your father.
谢谢
Thank you.
抱歉
Sorry.
没事的，我醒了
It's okay. I'm up.
现在什么时候了？
What time is it?
是你该拿出上等香槟庆祝的时候了
It's time you open that bottle you've been hiding.
你有突破了，是吧？
You cracked something, didn't you?
嗯，快过来
Yeah, come here.
瞧瞧这部分
Take a look at this section.
好像跟时间有关
It seems to be talking about time.
他们表示“时间”的符号无处不在
Their symbol for "time" is everywhere.
这到底说的什么？
So, what is this?
超光速旅行的方案吗？
A formula for faster-than-light travel?
谁敢下结论？
Who can tell?
里面有大段空白
There are too many gaps.
全都不完整
Nothing's complete.
然后我恍然大悟
Then it dawned on me.
过来
Come here.
就这儿
Right here.
别盯着有字的区域，注意空白区域
Stop focusing on the ones, look at the zeroes.
整个空间里面，有数据的区域和空白区域各占了多少？
How much of this is data? How much of it is negative space?
我于是测了下
So, I measured it.
数据的比例是0.0833...
0.0833 recurring.
或许你想用分数来表达
Perhaps you'd like that as a fraction.
十二分之一
One of 12.
这里传达出的意思是，这只是十二块之一
What they're saying right here is that this is one of 12.
我们得到的只是全图的一块
We are part of a larger whole.
这也有可能是让我们十二方厮杀的诱饵
Or we're one of 12 contestants for the prize.
我们为什么要向他汇报？
Why do I have to talk to him?
我们都是在这为国效命
We're all working together here.
我们得联络其他着陆点
We need to talk to the other sites.
我们应该主动支援，帮他们理解从其他七肢桶那得到的信息
We need to help them with what they've gotten from the other heptapods.
你可别忘了，我们现在通讯管制了
In case you don't remember, we're blacked out.
中国才威胁说要摧毁他们那的飞船，我们只能靠自己了
China just threatened to destroy their shell. We're on our own.
可这给的提示是所有分块能组合起来
Yeah, but this says that all of the pieces fit together.
现在根本没人关心这些
And I'm telling you that no one else cares.
两小时前，我们从俄国的一个加密频道截取到一段音频
Two hours ago, we pulled this audio off a secure channel in Russia.
他们科学团队里的一名成员对外直播的
Someone on the science team there was broadcasting wide.
在他们的最后一次对话中，外星人是这样说的：“时候到了...
In their final session, the alien said, "There is no time.
”许多合而为一“
"Many become one."
我觉得我们把武器都给完了
I feel we have all been given weapons.
如果有人收到这个的话，请..
If anyone is receiving this, please...
我觉得...
Well, I mean,
他刚刚说的话可以有各种解读
there are a lot of ways you can interpret what he's saying.
不需要翻译来解读我也知道它的意思
I don't need an interpreter to know what this means.
俄国为了保密，刚刚处决了
Russia just executed one of their own experts
自己的一名专家
to keep their secrets.
“许多合而为一”可能只是他们想表达
"Many become one" could just be their way of saying,
“要进行一些组合”的意思
"Some assembly required."
为什么要分成块给我们？
Why hand it out to us in pieces?
为什么不给我们完整的？
Why not just give it all over?
让我们人类破天荒的合作一次，没有比这更好的办法了吧？
Well, what better way to force us to work together for once?
就算我相信你
Even if I did believe you,
你有天大的本事吗，能让其他国家乖乖配合
how in the world you gonna get anybody else to play along
交出他们的数据？
or give up their data?
我们提供自己的来作交换
We offer ours in return.
对
Yeah?
做交易吗？
What, trade?
这是非零和博弈
It's a non-zero sum game.
非零和博弈
"Non-zero sum game."
就是它
That's it.
太好了，谢谢
Yeah, thanks.
有9个着陆点都实行了彻底的通讯管制
Nine of the landing sites have gone total comms blackout.
要想联络他们，就只有开车去边境
Only way to reach them is to physically drive there and yell
让他们的边防人员传话，我们已经在办了，可这样肯定来不及
at the border guards, which we're doing, but it won't be fast enough.
一定有别的渠道来给他们发消息
There's got to be a way to... To get the message to them.
对我们的盟友可能有，不过到了这种局面，效果有限，也太迟了
To our allies maybe, but at this stage, it's too little too late.
世界大战一触即发，我们却还
What we need is to get all the other nations online
联络不上各方，当务之急
before one starts global war,
是让有关各国都恢复联网
and there's no way for us to reach them.
等下，先等会儿
Wait. Hold on a second.
有渠道
There is.
我们上方不就有吗
It's right above us.
可我们现在很难办到啊
That's problematic for us right now.
五角大楼确信我们这的“蛋壳”会实施报复
The Pentagon's convinced our shell will retaliate.
估计一个小时内就要下令疏散了
My guess is they'll order us to evacuate within the hour.
听我说，他们不是敌人
Look, they're not our enemy.
他们从未有过任何挑衅我们的行为
They've made no act of aggression towards us.
或许那就是他们的挑衅方式
Maybe this is their way of being aggressive.
那不是问题所在
That's not the question.
那问题是什么？
Well, what is the question?
我们如何能将你俩送回离地800米高的房间？
How do we get you back in that room when it's half a mile straight up?
我觉得任务都结束了
I think our work here is done.
现在交由我们的上级决断了
It's in the hands of our superiors now.
她又想搞什么名堂？
What the hell is she doing?
不，天啊，天啊
No. God. Oh, God. No.
科斯特洛？
Costello?
阿波特呢？
Where's Abbott?
“阿波特成了死的了”
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我们都很抱歉
We're sorry.
我需要你......
I need you to...
我需要你发消息给其它着陆点
I need you to send a message to the other sites.
路易丝有武器
使用武器
我不
I don't...
我不明白
I don't understand.
你们来这的目的是什么？
What is your purpose here?
我们来帮助人类
3000年后......
我们需要人类的帮助
你怎么能预知未来？
How can you know the future?
我不...
I don't...
我不明白
I don't understand.
这个孩子是谁？
Who is this child?
这个节目叫“爸爸妈妈与动物交谈”
The show is called Mommy and Daddy Talk to Animals.
路易丝能预知未来
武器能打开时光隧道
等下...
Wait.
别走，等下！
No... Wait!
- 班克斯博士！  - 路易丝！
- Dr. Banks!  - Louise!
你没事吧？
Are you all right?
- 你没事吧？  - 嗯
- Hey. You all right?  - Yeah.
过来吧，发生了什么？  - 我没事
- Here, come on. What happened?  - I'm fine.
我正想搞明白，这事关重大
Tried to figure it out. This is too big.
现在都不重要了，我们接到命令要疏散了
Doesn't matter now. We have orders to evacuate.
- 为什么？  - 俄国和苏丹会效仿中国
- Why?  - Russia and Sudan are following China.
伊恩，我不明白这是为什么
Ian. I don't understand why the...
帮帮我，妈妈
Help me, Mama.
路易丝
Louise?
天啊
Oh, my God.
妈妈！
Mom.
妈妈!
Mama!
抱歉，宝贝
Sorry, honey.
今天星期几，宝贝你知道吗？
What day is it? Do you know, baby?
星期天
Sunday.
你要像爸爸那样离开我吗？
Are you gonna leave me like Daddy did?
汉娜宝贝，你爸爸没有离开你
Hannah, honey, your daddy didn't leave you.
你会见到他的，就这个周末
You're gonna see him this weekend.
他看我的眼神和以前不同了
He doesn't look at me the same way anymore.
这要怪我
That's my fault.
我跟他说了些事，他一时半会儿没法接受
I told him something that he wasn't ready to hear.
什么事？
What?
信不信由你
Well, believe it or not,
我知道将来会发生的事
I know something that's going to happen.
我也没法解释清楚，我就是知道
I can't explain how I know. I just do.
在我告诉你爸爸后，他气坏了
And when I told your daddy, he got really mad.
他说我做了错误的选择
And he said I made the wrong choice.
将来会发生什么？
What? What's going to happen?
会发生的事和一种罕见的疾病有关
It has to do with a really rare disease.
并且这种病是势不可挡的
And it's unstoppable.
有点像你一样
Kind of like you are.
你是如此神奇，你的诗歌
Your swimming, and your poetry,
还有你给世界增添的各种美好事物
and all the other amazing things that you share with the world.
我势不可挡？
I am unstoppable?
嗯
Yeah.
我扶着你
I got you.
路易丝
Louise?
Louise.
我刚得知丈夫为何离开我
I just realized why my husband left me.
我丈夫离开了我
My husband left me.
你已经结婚了？
You were married?
我们赶紧走吧
Come on. Let's get out of here.
妈妈？
Mama?
嗯？
Yeah?
我的名字为什么叫“汉娜”
Why is my name Hannah?
嗯，就在这里
Yeah, got it right here.
把这些人送出去
Get those people back, please.
你的名字很特别，因为它是回文
Well, your name is very special because it is a palindrome.
顺读倒读均相同的字
It reads the same forward and backward.
- 好了，大伙来帮帮我  - 好的，长官
- All right, guys, give me a hand here.  - Yes, sir.
把它放到那里
That goes in the back.
平民承包商准备好授权证章和口令
Civilian contractors must have their authorization badges
以备检查
and passkeys when checking...
宇宙文
疏散进行中...
Evacuation underway...
赠与汉娜
嘿！
Hey.
我们得走了
Look, we're done here.
我们把它带走就是了
We're taking this with us.
宇宙文 — 著者：路易丝
七文翻译指南
我看得懂
I can read it.
- 我知道它的意思  - 你说什么?
- I know what it is.  - What?
这不是什么武器，这是件礼物
It's not a weapon, it's a gift.
武器是指他们的语言
The weapon is their language.
他们全都交给了我们，你明不明白？
They gave it all to us. Do you understand what that means?
让我们学他们的语言？先保命再说吧
So we can learn Heptapod, if we survive.
你去学习的话，并且当你真正精通后
If you learn it, when you really learn it,
你就会用他们的方式感知时间
you begin to perceive time the way that they do.
这样你就能知道将来会发生什么
So you can see what's to come.
而且，他们所理解的时间和我们并不相同
But time, it isn't the same for them.
- 是非线性的  - 听着
- It's non-linear.  - Look.
我们竭尽所能了，可还是差一点
We did our best, but it wasn't enough.
你们跟这位上尉走
The captain will load you up.
5分钟后起飞
You're lifting off in five minutes.
伊恩，路易丝，跟你们共事是我的荣幸
Ian, Louise, it was an honor to work with ya.
一路顺风
Good luck.
上校
Hey, Colonel!
我去问下我们的目的地
I'm gonna find out where we're going.
醒醒，妈妈
Wake up, Mommy.
班克斯博士
Dr. Banks.
很荣幸
A pleasure.
尚将军
General Shang.
是我很荣幸才对
The pleasure is mine, really.
你们的总统说
Your President said
能邀请我参加这个宴会是很荣幸的事
he was honored to host me at the celebration...
- 是啊  - 可我要坦白
- Yes.  - ...but I confess,
我出席的唯一原因是
the only reason why I'm here is to
想亲自见你一面
meet you in person.
我？真是受宠若惊，谢谢你
Me? Well, I'm flattered. Thank you.
18个月前
Now, 18 months ago,
你做了件了不起的事
you did something remarkable.
连我上司都没这个本事
Something not even my superior has done.
是什么事？
And what's that?
你改变了我的心意
You changed my mind.
你是我们能联合起来的原因
You're the reason for this unification.
全靠你拨通了我的私人号码
All because you reached out to me on my private number.
你的私人号码
Your private number.
将军，我并不知道啊
General, I don't know your private number.
现在你知道了
Now you know.
我不是想说能看穿你的心思
I do not claim to know how your mind works,
不过我相信这号码你一定得看一眼
but I believe it was important for you to see that.
我的确打了你的电话，对吧？
I called you, didn't I?
是的，你打了
Yes, you did.
路易丝
Louise.
好了，都关机吧  - 长官
- All right, let's shut down the system.  - Sir.
这里有部卫星电话正打给中国
There's a sat-line here dialing China.
这里？你什么意思？
Here? What do you mean "here"?
快接啊
Come on, come on.
那是谁的电话？
Whose phone is it?
是你的电话，长官
It's your phone, sir.
搜索营地，马上去办
Search base camp now.
给我找出用电话的人
Find out who's using that phone.
- 盯着它的位置  - 遵命
- Hold on to those coordinates.  - Yes, sir.
快接，我该说什么？
Come on. What'd I say?
我该说什么？快接
What'd I say? Come on.
快接
Come on.
你跟我说的话，我会永生难忘
I will never forget what you said.
你跟我说了我妻子的临终遗言
You told me my wife's dying words.
将军
我在美国营地
将军，你夫人给我托梦了
妻子的遗愿，你应凭借勇气来......
她说你应凭借......
我们找到电话源头了
Found the source of the phone call.
就在清理间，等候指示
It's in the clean room. Waiting for instructions.
应凭借勇气来帮助拯救世界
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
- 你在做什么？  - 让一个人改变心意
- What are you doing?  - Changing someone's mind.
- 能帮我争取20秒钟吗？  - 我们来不及了
- Can you buy me 20 seconds?  - We don't have time for this right now.
来得及，相信我，帮我争取20秒，你相信我吗？
No, trust me, buy me 20 seconds. Do you trust me?
- 好吧  - 你相信我吗？
- Okay! Yeah.  - You trust me?
将军，她还说
班克斯博士
Dr. Banks!
马上放下电话，不然我们要开枪了
Drop the phone now or we shoot!
战争，不成就英雄
- 放下！  - 我很抱歉
- Drop it!  - Yeah. I'm sorry!
（战争）只会留下孤儿寡母
你现在的行为是叛国！
You're committing an act of treason!
- 是的  - 放下
- Yes.  - Drop it!
打完了，我打完了
It's done. I'm done.
谢谢你
谢谢
12个着陆点的通讯管制今晚仍在持续
Communications blackout from all 12 landing sites continues this evening.
等下，我们刚收到消息
Hold on, we are just hearing...
我接到通知
And I'm being told
现在我们要中断这则报道，插播突发新闻
we're going to cut this report to tell you breaking news.
突发新闻 中国突然召开了一场新闻发布会
Breaking now, China has called an emergency press conference.
中国人民解放军总司令，尚将军
General Shang, Commander-in-chief of the People's Liberation Army,
在新闻发布会上宣布
has announced in an emergency press conference
中国会立即撤军
that China is standing down.
中国宣布，他们收集到的所有情报
China is stating that all intelligence they have received
将会立即和其他着陆点分享
will be shared immediately with all the other landing sites.
世界各地的科学家正认真审查来自英国、日本
Scientists from around the world are sifting through information received
- 等国的信息  - 突发新闻
- from the UK, Japan...  - Breaking news,
俄罗斯军队现在公开了他们从自己
the Russian armed forces are now revealing the information
两个着落点收集到的信息
they've acquired from both of their landing sites
并宣布黑海为非军事区
and have declared the Black Sea a demilitarized zone.
谜题的十二个分块正被慢慢的拼到一起
...one of the 12 pieces of this puzzle that's being slowly put together.
所以，汉娜
So, Hannah.
这就是你故事的源头
This is where your story begins.
他们离去的那天
The day they departed.
你没事吧？
You all right?
尽管已提前知晓人生以及它的走向
Despite knowing the journey and where it leads,
我无所畏惧
I embrace it,
并且会珍惜每一分钟
and I welcome every moment of it.
H-A-N 汉， N-A-H 娜
- H-A-N-N-A-H.  - H-A-N-N-A-H.
现在反过来念  H-A-N 汉， N-A-H 娜
- Now backward. H-A-N-N-A-H.  - A-N-N-A-H.
汉娜
Hannah.
你准备好了，宝贝？
You ready, baby?
好了
Okay.
嗨
Hi.
- 好了吗？  - 好了，你去吧
- You good?  - All right. See ya.
爸爸
Daddy!
你没事吧？
You okay?
让爸爸从你身上翻过去
Daddy's gonna roll over you.
你准备好了？
All right, you ready?
今天讲星星的故事哦
Guess what? Star stuff.
- 嗯  - 嗯
- Yeah.  - Yeah.
如果你能一览自己的人生，从出生到死亡
If you could see your whole life from the start to finish,
你会尝试改变吗？
would you change things?
我或许...会尽量多吐露心声
Maybe I'd say what I feel more often.
天晓得呢
I... I don't know.
你知道吗，从我能记事起，我就总是对天上的星星着迷
You know, I've had my head tilted up to the stars for as long as I can remember.
可你知道什么让我最惊喜吗？
You know what surprised me the most?
并不是遇见他们
It wasn't meeting them.
而是遇见你
It was meeting you.
被你抱着的感觉还是如此温暖啊
I forgot how good it felt to be held by you.
你想生个宝宝吗？
You wanna make a baby?
想
Yes.
想啊
Yeah.
降临
译者：danassus